cigar.com 2019-07-17

# Help - Privacy Page - CIGAR.com

Back  
To  
Top

## Privacy Policy

The following Privacy Policy describes how we gather information from our customers and other visitors, the types of information we gather, how we use it, and how we protect it. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this policy, you may contact us at any time.

We will not sell, share, or rent your information to others in any ways different from those disclosed in this Policy.

Please take a moment to read this Privacy Policy for a better understanding of the measures we take to protect you and the information you share with us. By visiting this website, you are accepting the practices described below.

## Your California Privacy Rights

"Do Not Track" (or DNT) is a preference you can set in your browser to let the websites you visit know that you do not want them to collect information about you. If you do not want your personal information shared with third parties for this purpose, you can opt out by contacting us.

We **do not** support " _do not track_ " requests.

## What Information We Collect

We gather and store the information you enter on our web site or give us in other ways. You can choose not to provide certain information, but you may not be able to take advantage of key features of online shopping.

To process your order, we require you to supply us with your billing (credit card), shipping and contact information (email address and phone number). The transfer of this information is secure and cannot be received or read by others. Your credit card information is only shared with our bank for authorization.

## Why We Collection Information

We gather information about you so that you may quickly navigate our site for products of interest and to place orders. We also gather information so that we can improve your experience at this website. By collecting information, we are able to offer you features (such as login and password information) that save you time during the order process.

## How We Collect Information

When you create your account, and during the order process, you are prompted to supply us with your contact, billing, and shipping information. This information must be provided in order to complete a purchase and is used to complete your order and contact you regarding your order.

## Cookies

We also use cookies to collect information from you. Cookies are pieces of information stored locally on your computer that are used by us and by third parties (see Google Analytics, below).

We use first party cookies to identify how you arrived at our site. A cookie identifies you while you are at our site and keeps track of items in your shopping cart between visits. We use this information to view bounce rates, content consumed, time on site, cart/conversion activity and more.

Cookies never contain credit card information.

## Use of Information We Collect

**GOOGLE ANALYTICS**

We use Google Analytics and other similar services to track website visitor activity at both the aggregate and individual level. We’ve enabled user ID tracking in Google Analytics, which allows Google to track your web activity and online behavior. However, the user ID is still anonymous to us. Google uses this information to personalize advertisements to you for goods and services.

To learn about Google’s privacy practices, [click here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

You can opt out of having your information used by Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. To access and use the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

We also use Adobe Analytics and Test & Target to analyze and optimize the performance of our websites. To learn about Adobe’s privacy policies or to opt out of Adobe Analytics tracking, [click here](http://www.adobe.com/privacy.html).

 **THIRD PARTIES**

We engage third parties to perform services such as payment processing and authorization, fraud protection and credit risk reduction, product customization, order fulfillment and shipping, marketing and promotional material distribution, web site evaluation, data analysis and, where applicable, data cleansing. We provide your personal information to these third parties, but we authorize them to use this information only in connection with the services they perform.

To opt-out of receiving online display advertisements tailored to your interests by our third party partners, visit the Network Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices). You can also set a Do Not Track preference in your browser.

We also partner with companies that offer products and services we believe may be of interest to our customers. If you purchase a product from us, we may share your name with another company whose products and services might interest you. If you do not want to have your name shared for this purpose, contact us at any time.

Our web site may use SessionCam for analysis. SessionCam is a product that has been developed by SessionCam LTD. SessionCam may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, page scrolling and any text keyed into website forms. The information collected does not include bank details or any sensitive personal data. Data collected by SessionCam from "insert company name" website is for "insert company name" internal use only. The information collected is used to improve our website usability and is stored and used for aggregated and statistical reporting.

 **EMAILS**

We use your email address to send order confirmation emails and invoices. If you have selected to receive our weekly email specials by supplying your email address, we will send you our exclusive weekly specials. You can opt out of receiving promotional emails from us by clicking “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any email.

 **CATALOG REQUESTS**

You may receive printed catalogs from us. If you wish to be removed from our mailing list, contact us at any time.

## Change Your Information

You can contact us anytime to modify your personal information. **We cannot change your personal information over the phone.** Additionally, you have the ability to change your personal information any time you log into your account.

## Opt Out

You may, at any time, opt out of receiving communications from us, either by clicking "unsubscribe" at the bottom of any e-mail or you can contact us directly and we will take care of it for you immediately

## Links to Other Sites

This website may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites.

## Security

We have implemented systems and procedures to secure the information we collect online. For example, we protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts the information you input. This industry standard encrypts all of your information, including credit card numbers, so that it cannot be read by others as the information is exchanged via the Internet.

Additionally, it is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. If you use a shared computer, be sure to sign off and close all browsers when you are finished.

## Age Verification

##### Why do we verify your age?

We do not sell our products to anyone under the age of 21. We use a non-affiliated third party company, Veratad Technologies, LLC, to verify that you are who you say you are and to confirm that you are 21 or older.

##### How does Veratad’s Age Verification work?

Veratad Age and Identity Verification Solutions Veratad’s AgeMatch Age Verification services use multiple trusted data sources containing billions of public records to return an age validation based on the personal information you submit. This service is specifically designed to validate and protect your identity while maintaining the highest level of consumer privacy when processing online transactions.

Access to the public records allows Veratad to validate the information you provide and in some cases, depending on the nature of your purchase, to present a series of multiple choice questions based on non-credit related (“out-of-wallet”) historical facts about you. These facts are obtained by instantaneously scanning billions of public records from trusted data sources containing information that would not generally be found in your wallet if lost or stolen.

##### Is the information I provide secure?

Veratad’s secure 256 bit encryption technology ensures the safe delivery of the information you provide online. In addition, Veratad **DOES NOT** store your sensitive personal information or share (or sell) any data with other third parties. This practice assures you that unauthorized parties cannot gain access to your sensitive personal information.

##### What happens if I cannot be verified by the Age Verification process?

A small percentage of shoppers may not be verifiable due to limited availability of publicly available information in the age verification databases. If this happens, we will attempt to contact you via phone and email to verify your age. We typically require a copy of your driver’s license or some other form of government issued ID that verifies your date of birth.

##### I live outside of the U.S. Can I be verified?

Our use of Veratad’s Age Verification is based solely on U.S. records and therefore verification of individuals residing outside the U.S. is unavailable, unless you are using a military address outside the U.S. Individuals in all other countries will be subject to our manual review process described in the previous section.

## Notification of Changes

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make material changes to this Policy, we will update this page and the effective date listed below.

 **EFFECTIVE DATE:** April 20, 2016
